

# Cristian López Fernández

□ (+34) 667 82 61 26 | ☑ crilopfer@gmail.com | ☑ crilofer | 匝 crilopfer | У @crilofer

"Never try, never know."

# Summary.

I've continuously worked in software engineering for my whole 7+ year career.

Over my career I've had the chance to participate in several projects and contributed to different types of system architectures, teams, products and overall tech ecosystems.

At my current professional position, I am responsible for multiple distributed backend teams, alongside coordinating with frontend teams and other stakeholders. My main work specifically focusses on complex architectural decisions regarding company-wide services scalability, security and reliability.

I seek to leverage my knowledge and experience to help build customer-centric features in the product area, leading teams and helping in technical architectural designs.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_

**Tymit** London (United Kingdom)

March 2021 - Present ENGINEERING LEAD

I was promoted to Lead position. Key responsabilities about this role are:

- · Managing engineering team
- Design scalable, reliable and secure architecture solutions
- To be involved with stakeholders and product in the company roadmap decisioning
- Continue contributing to product with customer features implementation

Tech stack: Quarkus, Java 11+, JUnit, Micronaut, Kotlin, Grails, Groovy, Spock, AWS (SQS, SNS, RDS, EC2, SES, CloudWatch, API Gateway), PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Docker, Kibana, Grafana, Prometheus.

Tymit London (United Kingdom)

PRINCIPAL SOFTWARE ENGINEER

February 2018 - March 2021

#### Employee no. 1

I started the project from scratch. At the very beginning, in order to get an early MVP, we built a monolith system based on Grails and Groovy. After 1 year and due to the growth of the company, we started migrating our monolith architecture to microservices architecture using Quarkus and Java. The main reasons for that were scalability, continuous integration and understanding of the domain model of the business.

I have been involved in the whole business growth process of the company, taking decisions with stakeholders and contributing with new features for product area.

As part of the team's growth, I have been mentoring all of them, giving support and helping in the onboarding task.

Some of the **customer features** I have implemented at Tymit:

- Wallets integration (Apple Pay & Google Pay)
- Open Banking: Payment Initiation Services (PIS) & Account Information Services (AIS)
- Real time authorizations / transactions / payments, 3D Secure
- KYC

Tech stack: Quarkus, Java 11+, JUnit, Micronaut, Kotlin, Grails, Groovy, Spock, AWS (SQS, SNS, RDS, EC2, SES, CloudWatch, API Gateway), PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Docker, Kibana, Grafana, Prometheus.

**Universidad Rey Juan Carlos** 

Madrid (Spain)

ASSOCIATE LECTURER

January 2019 - August 2021

Associate Lecturer in the Department of Computing Science, Computer Architecture, Programming Languages and Systems and Statistics and Operative Investigation.

I was in charge of the following subjects:

- High Performance Computing
- · Distributed systems
- Development of applications for mobile devices

Santander UK London (United Kingdom)

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

September 2017 - February 2018

Participating in several projects from a R&D department.

- Implementing Blockchain solution for internal project
- Leading OCR project for Identity document verification

Tech stack: Java 11, Kotlin, Apache Kafka, Corda, Tesseract, Spring Boot, JUnit, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Docker.

BABEL Madrid (Spain)

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

October 2015 - September 2017

As it is a consulting company, I was participating in several projects from different companies like **BBVA**, **Orange**, **Telefónica**, **Sanitas**, **HM Hospitales**, among others.

Although I participated as individual contributor most of the time, I had the opportunity of leading some teams (5-6 people) as Team lead using agile methodologies, supporting them on the technical area, contributing on technical design sessions, etc.

Tech stack: Java 11, Java 8, PHP, Python, Spring Boot, JUnit, Django, Liferay, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB.

Grupo Comunica Córdoba (Spain)

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

May 2013 - September 2014

- · Participating in the development of Android & iOS applications
- Implementing Audio-Visual streaming project

Tech stack: Java, Android SDK, Objective-C, Spring Boot, JUnit, PHP, MySQL.

## **Education**

Universidad de Granada Granada Granada (Spain)

MASTER'S DEGREE, DATA SCIENCE AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING (GRADE: A)

2014 - 2015

• Master's Thesis: SmartARGlass - Augmented Reality on smart devices

Universidad de Córdoba Córdoba (Spain)

DEGREE, COMPUTER ENGINEERING (GRADE: B+)

2010 - 2014

• End-of-Degree project: RPiDomotic - Domotic system using Raspberry Pi

### About Me\_

I love Amazon Alexa and I am contributing with skills implementations about education, mental health and leisure.

Also, I am Open Water Diver by SSI International.